gudli.com 2015-09-10

# Privacy Policy - TurtleDiary.com

Privacy Policy

### Our Commitment To Privacy

Turtlediary knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Policy sets out the terms of how Turtlediary uses and protects any personal information that you provide Turtlediary when you use the website www.TurtleDiary.com (the Website). It also explains each parent's or guardian's (Parent) ability to review, request deletion of, or place certain restrictions on the collection, use, and disclosure of, personal information of his/her Child. Turtlediary is committed to ensuring that your child's privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you or your child can be identified when using this Website, you can be assured that it will only be used pursuant to this privacy policy and/or pursuant to our Terms and Conditions. Turtlediary may revise this policy at any time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are in agreement with any changes. Continued use of this Website constitutes your agreement to our then-current privacy policy. This policy is effective as of March 20th, 2013. 

**This policy will answer the following questions:**

  * What personally identifiable information does Turtlediary collect from me?
  * What are cookies and how does Turtlediary use them?
  * Who is collecting information?
  * What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?
  * What is Turtlediary's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?
  * What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?
  * How does Turtlediary protect children's privacy?
  * What else should I know about my privacy?
  * Additional Information

### What personally identifiable information does Turtlediary collect from me?

Turtlediary collects information in several ways from different parts of our products.

Some personal information is gathered when you register. Depending on your account type, Turtlediary may ask for your name, e-mail address, and/or additional information. We may also ask you to choose a username and password. This information is used to activate additional features of the Website, to purchase products and to view secure content. In the event that you purchase a subscription, we ask for credit card data and other payment and billing information.

In addition to the information we collect when you register, we may ask you for personal information at other times, such as when you contact our technical support team. Furthermore, when you send e-mails, user surveys, contests or other communication to Turtlediary, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve our services. Please note that participation in surveys and contests is completely voluntary.

* * *

### What are cookies and how does Turtlediary use them?

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Turtlediary uses cookies to temporarily store information about you. A cookie is a small file on your own computer containing a string of characters that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to better display our website, to save you time, to provide better technical support, for advertising purposes, and to anonymously track website usage. For example, cookies help us to:

  * Keep track of whether you are signed in or have previously signed in so that we can display all the features that are available to you.
  * Remember your settings on the pages you visit, so that we can display your preferred content the next time you visit.
  * Know your username when you submit a technical support request so that you don't have to type it in.
  * Advertise to potential customers on other websites around the web.
  * Anonymously track website usage in the aggregate to help improve our services.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features and services of the Website (particularly those that require you to sign in) may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data that you choose to share with us.

* * *

### How does Turtlediary use my information?

Turtlediary's goals in collecting personal information are to provide you and your child, the user, with a customized experience on our sites and a high level of technical support.

Turtlediary does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, from our server log files, or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users; for instance, this information often gives us ideas for improving our products. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis.

* * *

### Who is collecting information?

When you are on the Turtlediary site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Turtlediary alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. If data is being collected or maintained by any company other than Turtlediary, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer.

* * *

As a general rule, Turtlediary will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. The following describes some of the reasons that your information may be disclosed.

_**Business Partners & Sponsors**_. Turtlediary will never disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, unless it is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. If Turtlediary becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

_**Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate**_. Under confidentiality agreements, Turtlediary may match user information with third party data. Also, Turtlediary discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 8% of our users are from California) in order to describe our services to current and prospective partners and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

_**Other**_. Turtlediary may release personal information if it has a good faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof; (c) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of Turtlediary, its users, or the public as required or permitted by law.

* * *

### What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?

Turtlediary may, from time to time, send you e-mail regarding our products and services. Only Turtlediary will send you these direct mailings. You can choose not to receive these e-mails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any e-mail or contacting [support@turtlediary.com](mailto:support@turtlediary.com). 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. However, if you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Turtlediary services, which require registration in order to participate. 

Turtlediary does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service. 

* * *

### What is Turtlediary's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?

You may edit your account information at any time by logging into your account and clicking the Account or Profile link. We recommend that you review your personal information periodically to ensure that it is accurate, complete, and current.

If you have forgotten your password, go to the password request form. A new password will be sent to the e-mail address you specified during registration. For all other problems logging into Turtlediary services, please contact technical support for that service.

Please contact technical support for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your account for any Turtlediary service. Residual information will remain within our archive records.

* * *

### What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage, and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. However, the internet is an open system and we cannot provide absolute assurances that transmissions or data cannot be intercepted or decrypted by others.

Your registered accounts are password-protected so that you and only you have access to any personal information you have entered in your account. You may edit your account information at any time by logging into your account and clicking the Account or Profile link.

For your protection, remember to log out of all accounts before closing your browser. There is a log out link available on most Turtlediary pages. After logging out, make sure to close all browser windows. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information if you share a computer with someone else or are using a public computer.

We restrict access to personal information to Turtlediary employees, contractors, and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop, or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

* * *

### How does Turtlediary protect children's privacy?

Turtlediary is committed to protecting the safety and wellbeing of children, and we continually work to ensure that our data collection practices conform to all applicable laws, including the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

We are required by law to obtain parental consent in order to collect, use, or disclose Personal Information from Children who are under 13 years of age. Turtlediary does not ask a child under age 13 for more personal information, as a condition of participation, than is reasonably necessary to participate in a given activity. Such personal information may include the child's name and email address as gathered upon registration, messages that the child may post via message boards or chat rooms, email inquiries as well as information gathered passively via Cookies. Turtlediary does not gather information on the ages of our users and will never knowingly share personally identifying information about users who are under the age of 13 with business partners or other third parties.

A Parent has the right to review their Child's personal information, either by logging in to the Child's account profile or by contacting us directly. A Parent may update their child's personal information directly in the account profile. Additionally, a Parent may ask us to delete their child's personal data and close the account, which would further prohibit future collection or use of the child's personal information. Upon such request, we will delete the Child's account and all the information and data stored for such account to the extent possible. When we delete such data, it will be deleted from our active databases but may remain in our archives. 

Turtlediary may (and the Parent authorizes us to) rely on the instructions that we reasonably believe are given by a Child's Parent. For example, if a person contacts our technical support and provides the requisite account information, we may assume that the person calling is the Child's Parent.

* * *

### What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online (for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas) that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Some Turtlediary services offer the option to show your name and e-mail address in various capacities. If you decide to show your name and e-mail address, you are making it available to others over the Internet.

Additionally, some Turtlediary services offer the ability to build custom Web pages or customize the content on a Web page. Just like any other Web-page building tool, the pages thus created can be accessed by anyone over the Internet. Please do not include any information on your Web page that you do not want to disclose over the Internet. PLEASE BE EXTREMELY CAREFUL WHEN DISCLOSING ANY INFORMATION IN CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS AND OTHER PUBLIC POSTING AREAS. WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE INFORMATION THAT YOU DISCLOSE IN SUCH CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS OR OTHER PUBLIC POSTING AREAS.

* * *

#### _Links to Third Party Websites_

Turtlediary may contain links to enable you to visit non-affiliated third party websites. However, by clicking on these third party links, you will effectively be leaving our Website. Note that we do not have any control over the content contained in any third party website featured on our Website. As such, Turtlediary is not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide any third party website and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and review the privacy policies for any third party website.

### Additional Information

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat your personal information by placing a prominent notice on our websites. Our privacy policy is current as of March 20th, 2013. 

This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions. In the event of a discrepancy between our Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions, the Terms and Conditions shall govern. If you feel that we are not abiding by this Privacy Policy or our Terms and Conditions, have a question regarding this statement, or if a question was not addressed in this privacy policy, you may contact technical support at support@turtlediary.com. We will do our best to answer your question promptly and accurately.
